Guide to the Milbank Memorial Fund Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1920-1990; Accession 1993-M-007; 5.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous files
    - A Survey of the Operations of the Fund Based Upon a Study of its Finances, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Answers to Questionnaire submitted by Select Committee of the House of Representatives of the Congress of the U. S. to Investigate Foundations and Other Organizations, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Milbank Memorial Committee on Readings in Health Planning, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund Board of Directors Committee on Planning, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Milbank Scholar Program, 1978-1982 (Box 3)
    - Milbank Scholar Program: site visits by D. Willis and R. Kasius, 1982 (Box 3)
    - "Adequate Minimum Standards for Personal Health Services"
      - Correspondence re discussions, 1976 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence re Round Table, 1977 (Box 4)
      - Report - Round Table, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Princeton University - Albert G. Milbank Professorship, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Dr. Frank Boudreau, President, 1937-1962 (Box 4)
    - Ernest Gruenberg, 1977-1991 (Box 4)
    - Milbank faculty fellows and members of the staff: photographs, undated (Box 4)
    - Pension plans of various colleges and universities, 1920, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Blue Cross - Community Blood Programs, 1965-1971 (Box 4)
  - Restricted
    Employee records are restricted for seventy-five years after the employee's termination date. Expiration dates of restrictions are indicated at the folder level.
    - Ex-employees' personal files
      - Blaser, Larry E., 1965 October 14-1973 May 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2049 due to repository requirement.
      - Brazaitis, Barbara Ann, 1962-1972 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2048 due to repository requirement.
      - Donnelly, Margaret Elizabeth (Perry), 1968 November 25-1972 January 31 (Box 5)
      - Dillon, Marianne, 1967 October 16-1976 October 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2052 due to repository requirement.
      - Redford, Maxine, 1982 September 20- 1984 December 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2060 due to repository requirement.
      - Stensland, Per G., 1965-1973 August 31 (Box 5)
      - Szczypkowski, Ronald, 1958 December 1-1971 September 15 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2047 due to repository requirement.
    - Retirees' personal files
      - Doran, Catherine A. (deceased 1977 May 28), 1921 March 7-1955 December 30 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2031 due to repository requirement.
      - Villalta, Olga, 1967 July 17-1978 October 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2054 due to repository requirement.
      - Downes, Jean (deceased 1968 Sep 30), 1926 October 11-1958 March 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2034 due to repository requirement.
      - Gensamer, Katherine, 1963 October 9-1973 June 30 (Box 5)
      - McGovern, Geraldine (deceased 1972 Apr 21), 1938 November 1-1956 August 7 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2032 due to repository requirement.
      - McGovern, Marcella (deceased 1969 Apr 14), 1930 March 3-1956 December 31 (Box 5)
      - Wiehl, Dorothy G. (deceased 1980 Jun 26), 1926 October 26-1963 December 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2039 due to repository requirement.
      - Williams, Frances (deceased 1981 Feb 14), 1931 March 19-1957 December 31 (Box 5)
        File is restricted until January 1, 2033 due to repository requirement.
- Additional material, 1977-1990; Accession 1993-M-009; 9.25 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Received from: Milbank Memorial Fund, 1992 July 28
  - Milbank Quarterly: miscellaneous correspondence, Circa 1977-1987
    - A-C (Box 1)
    - D-G (Box 2)
    - H-L (Box 3)
    - M-O (Box 4)
    - P-Si (Box 5)
    - So-Z (Box 6)
  - MIT journals correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Copyright Clearance Center, 1977-1982 (Box 7)
  - MIT Press: miscellaneous correspondence, 1977-1985 (Box 7)
  - Volumes 57-60 (1): miscellaneous correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - "Ethical Issues in Health Insurance": miscellaneous correspondence, 1989 (Box 7)
  - President's Commission for the Study of Ethical Problems in Medicine and Biomedical and Behavioral Research, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - AIDS Book, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Unsolicited manuscripts, 1977-1982 (Box 7)
  - Unsolicited manuscripts, 1983-1989 (Box 8)
  - Copyright, miscellaneous, 1977-1984 (Box 8)
- Additional material, 1913-1994; Accession 1995-M-181
  - Executive Committee minutes [five volumes including one index volume], 1922-1978 (Box 1)
  - Finance Committee minutes [eight volumes], 1970-1987 (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors' meetings [minutes, reports, etc.], 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors' meetings [minutes, reports, etc.], -1988 (Box 4)
  - Development grants files
    - A - I, 1961-1987 (Box 5)
    - I - U, 1970-1988 (Box 6)
  - Epidemiology fellowships, 1980-1984 (Box 7)
  - Occupational Health Grants files
    - A - F, 1986-1989 (Box 8)
    - F - N, 1986-1989 (Box 9)
    - O - U, 1986-1989 (Box 10)
    - U - Y, 1986-1989 (Box 11)
    - Unsorted, 1986-1989 (Box 11)
    - Program announcements, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Scholar Program files
    - General, 1978-1982 (Box 12)
    - Site visits, 1978-1984 (Box 12)
    - Announcements, lists, notes, etc., 1976-1982 (Box 12)
  - Awards
    - A - S, 1979-1988 (Box 13)
    - S - V, 1979-1988 (Box 14)
  - Special grants
    - A - H, 1975-1994 (Box 15)
    - I - Y, 1970-1989 (Box 16)
  - Milbank Quarterly correspondence
    - A - L, 1989-1991 (Box 17)
    - M - R, 1989 - 1992 (Box 18)
    - S - Z, 1949-1992 (Box 19)
  - Milbank, Tweed, Hadley, and McCloy correspondence
    - 1970-1972 (Box 19)
    - 1973-1984 (Box 20)
  - Abstracts of Appeals
    - 1921-1951 (Box 21)
    - 1952-1988 (Box 22)
    - 1989-1992 (Box 23)
    - Cumulative index, 1921-1992 (Box 23)
  - Investments performance reports, 1971-1983 (Box 23)
  - Budget and financial projections, 1978-1988 (Box 23)
  - Operational review, 1986-1987 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous files, 1913-1991 (Box 24)
  - John Kingsbury Papers [photocopies of originals in the Manuscripts Division of the Library of Congress], Circa 1919-1942 (Box 25)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 26)
- Additional material, Accession 2002-M-003
  - Publications
    - Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly
      - Financial, economic, and business aspects, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
      - Editorial Board correspondence, 1972-1990 (Box 1)
      - Search committee for editor [bills], 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Publications program
    - General, 1969-1992 (Box 1)
    - Budget, 1975-1992 (Box 1)
  - Publications
    - Contributions in name of Sarah Ottersbach, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Contract between Dartmouth Medical School and the fund [payments: editorial services], 1976-1978 (Box 2)
    - Affidavit in support of loss position, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Committee on readings in health planning [bills], 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - Clive Driver, manuscript editor [correspondence], 1983-1990 (Box 2)
  - Jersey Printing [Quarterly Report], 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Editor search, 1996-1999 (Box 3)
  - Editors of journals meeting, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Quarterly
    - Miscellaneous inquiries, etc., 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Copyright and Royalties, 1974-1990 (Box 3)
    - Basic information, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
    - Publisher survey, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
    - Editor's correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 3)
  - Milbank Scholars, 1980-1989 (Box 3)
- Additional material, Accession 2004-M-001
  - Readers' reports on submissions to The Milbank Quarterly [#95-00], 1998-2000 (Box 1)